(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-17T05:14:35.143365",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
もうハイになっちゃうよね オッケー？
We're already getting high, right? Okay?
受け取ってよね オッケー？
Accept it, right? Okay?
きみのことが好き、だもん
Because I love you so much!
はっぴー
Happy!
いい感じって勘違いしちゃって
It feels so right...
恥ずかしくなっちゃうじゃん
It gets so embarrassing, right?
バカバカ！
You're such a fool!
あー待って
Ah, wait!
それ以上わたしに近付かないで
Don't get any closer to me than that!
caution caution!
押し込んだ感情が脱走脱走
My pent-up emotions are running wild!
想いのドミノ倒してみて
Just try tipping over your desires.
止まらなくて困るかも
It might be a problem if it doesn't stop.
言いたいこと全部言えちゃう魔法を とろけちゃうくらいの砂糖を
Sprinkle it with enough sugar to melt away
たっぷりかけて
all the things I want to say!
それではっぴーじゃん きみが笑うなら
Then it's happy if you smile!
それがはっぴーじゃん
That's happy, too!
心スキップしてジャンプして
With a skip in my heart and a jump,
落ち込んでだめだめだって
even if I feel down and hopeless,
一回のきみの笑顔で全部忘れちゃうから
your single smile makes me forget it all!
もう何をやったってはい、オッケー
No matter what happened, yes, okay?
謝ったらはい、オッケー
If I apologized, yes, okay?
甘え過ぎたら「めっ！」ってしといてね
If I rely on you too much, scold me with a "Hey!", okay?
もうハイになっちゃうよね オッケー？
We're already getting high, right? Okay?
受け取ってよね オッケー？
Accept it, right? Okay?
きみのことが好きなんだもん
Because I love you so much!
伝えたい言葉があふれ出す気持ちが
Feelings overflowing with words I want to tell you,
きみを目指してまた大渋滞して
aiming for you and causing another traffic jam.
鳴り響くクラクション
A resonating cacophony.
思い切っちゃえば快勝？
Is it victory if I just make up my mind?
踏んでしまうのはいつもブレーキなんだよ
What stomps it down is always the brakes.
想いのオセロ返ししてみて
Try returning your feelings' ocelot,
挟まれたら染まるかも
if you get cornered, you might get dyed in them.
言いたいこと全部言えちゃう魔法で
With magic to say all the things I want to say,
とろけちゃうくらいの砂糖で ドキドキさせたい
and plenty of sugar to make you melt and flutter your heart,
でもあんぱいじゃん 見てくれなくちゃ
but that's not quite happy yet!
またあんぱいじゃん 心フリックしてショートして
That's not quite happy yet either!
おねだりしてみてほしいの ダーリン
Please try asking me, darling!
あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
You never listen to a single word I say.
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
Even though I told you to quit smoking and drinking,
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず
you have two packs and seven cans every single day without fail.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても
Even if your liver gives out and you become a wreck,
看病してあげないんだから
I'm not going to nurse you back to health!
まああ言うやこう言うって何処でもきかない
No matter what anyone says, you never listen.
あなたのハートは真っ黒です
Your heart is pitch black.
言いいたいことは言わないし
You never say what you want to say,
行き先もやりたいことも決める癖してだんまりさん
and while you decide where to go, you stay completely silent.
ねえそんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない? そうじゃない? じゃない? じゃない?
Hey, isn't that ridiculous? Isn't it? Isn't it? Isn't it?
言いたいことあるならさっさと言えば?
If you have something to say, why don't you just spit it out?
いつも思い過ごしな感じで 察してほしい感じで
You always expect me to overthink and read between the lines,
わざわざ口にしないのずるくない? 馬鹿じゃないの?
and never say it out loud. Isn't that unfair? Are you an idiot?
おねだりダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, darling, look and listen. What I want is something intangible.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ瞳の奥の方
I won't make fun of you, so look and listen, and peek deep into my eyes.
真っ直ぐ見つめて おねだりしてみて 欲しいの? ダーリン
Look straight at me. Can you ask me properly? Do you want it, darling?
私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないの
I have no idea how you actually feel.
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに 今ではすっかり知らんぷり
Even though I looked at you so devotedly back then, now you completely pretend you don't know.
ていうかそれって胡坐かいてるだけなんじゃないんですかぶっちぎけ
Or rather, aren't you just taking me for granted? Absolutely outrageous!
舌先三寸 あなたのお陰で私のハートはボロボロです
Thanks to your silver tongue, my heart is completely shattered.
つれない時はつれないし
When you're cold, you're really cold,
そっちが中々言い出さないから いつも私が舵取りじゃん?
and since you never speak up, I always end up taking the helm, right?
ねえ なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない? そうじゃない? じゃない? じゃない?
Hey, don't you think that's kind of stupid? Don't you? Don't you? Don't you?
どこか足元見てる感じで 足踏みされてる感じで
You always act like you've got the upper hand, trampling all over my feelings.
駆け引きやら勝ち負けじゃない? 寡黙なダーリン ねえ聞いて
Isn't this all about mind games? Silent darling, hey, listen to me.
切なさは飾りじゃないのよ よそ見しないで 逃げないで
Heartache isn't just for show. Don't look away, don't run away.
触ってよ心の奥の方 一瞬のことじゃない
Touch the depths of my heart. This isn't just a fleeting moment.
おねだりしてはくれないの? 言葉に出せない臆病さは
Won't you beg me for once? The cowardice you can't put into words
強さではないのよ 甘えてないで口に出してよ
isn't strength. Stop acting shy and say it out loud!
おねだり ダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, darling, look and listen. What I want is something intangible.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ瞳の奥の方
I won't make fun of you, so look and listen, and peek deep into my eyes.
寡黙な ダーリン 寝てないで 暴いてよ私の素顔を
Silent darling, don't just sleep—expose my true self!
おねだり ダーリン そばにいて 触らせて私の奥の方
Please, darling, stay by my side. Let me touch the depths of your heart.
真っ直ぐ見つめて おねだりしてみてほしいの
Look straight at me. I want you to ask me properly.
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたい
Gotta get muscle! Please, that's all I need!
お願いマッスル めっちゃ痩せたい
Gotta get muscle! Shaping up my body, yes!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたいから
Gotta get muscle! Please, that's all I need!
うー! (キレてるよ!) はー! (キレてるよ!)
Woo! (You're getting it!) Ha! (You're getting it!)
筋肉にお願い
Please give me muscles soon!
ヒップレイズ!サイドベント!腹筋6LDK!
Hip raise! Side bend! Flexing my 6-pack!
ダンベルカール!ハンマーカール!二頭がいいね!チョモランマ!
Dumbbell curl! Hammer curl! Biceps harder than rock! Chomolungma!
プッシュアップ!ベンチプレス!大胸筋が歩いてる!
Push-up! Bench press! Gotta work those enormous pecs!
仕上がってるよ!仕上がってるよ!筋肉本舗!はい、どーーーん!
You're looking great! Muscle headquarters! Boom!
理想の自分を思い描いたら 今すぐ始めよトレーニング (ゲット マッスル)
If you want to reach your goals, start training right now! (Get muscle!)
ヤバめの現実とかなるはず ダンベル両手にフリーウェイト (ナイスマッショ)
Before reality gets you down, with a dumbbell in hand! (Nice macho!)
焦りは禁物 無理しちゃ沈没 負荷のかけ方を調節 (そう 筋肉)
Pace yourself and adjust the load! (So muscle!)
限界10回ギリギリ全開 3セットしたらオーライ (ナイスポーズ)
Push to the limit with 3 sets of 10 reps! (Nice form!)
辛いこともある筋肉道 モテモテボディが欲しいの!
Pushing through the pain, I want a body that turns heads!
綺麗なワタシに大変身 見てなさい!サイドチェストーーー!
Transform into a gorgeous me! Just watch! Side chest pose!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたい
Gotta get muscle! Please, that's all I need!
お願いマッスル めっちゃ痩せたい
Gotta get muscle! Shaping up my body, yes!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたいなら
Gotta get muscle! Please, that's all I need!
うー! (キレてるよ!) はー! (キレてるよ!)
Woo! (You're getting it!) Ha! (You're getting it!)
筋肉にお願い
Please give me muscles soon!
レッグカール!ハックリフト!泣く子も黙る大腿四頭筋!
Leg curl! Hack lift! Let those incredible thighs get ripped!
バックプレス!サイドレイズ!肩にちっちゃい重機のせてんのかい!
Back press! Side raise! You got heavy machinery on your shoulders!
ベントオーバー!ラットプルダウン!背中に鬼神が宿ってる!
Bend over! Lat pulldown! Almighty traps really draw in a crowd!
仕上がってるよ!仕上がってるよ!頑張るあなたは美しい!
You're looking great! All your hard work makes you beautiful!
昨日の今日では効果がなくても とにかく続けよトレーニング (超マッスル)
Even if you don't see results right away, just keep pushing! (Super muscle!)
気分を変えたい?混みすぎて辛い?それならマシンでワークアウト!
Want to change things up? Gym too crowded? Try a machine workout!
けど食べるの大切 筋肉の秘訣 食事で体を建設! (ボディビルディング!)
Nutrition is key! Build your body with proper food! (Bodybuilding!)
3日に1回?週に2～3回?無理ないペースでおっけー! (バルク!)
Every three days? Twice a week? Go at a pace that works for you! (Bulk!)
めげそうな時思い出して “努力”が報われれば
Whenever you feel like giving up, remember your hard work will pay off.
美肌も手に入れて 見せつけたいでしょ 脚線美
Get smooth skin and show off those gorgeous legs!
頑張ります!ます!ます!?モストマスキュラーーー!
Let's do our best! Most muscular pose!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたい
Gotta get muscle! Please, that's all I need!
お願いマッスル めっちゃ痩せたい
Gotta get muscle! Shaping up my body, yes!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたいなら
Gotta get muscle! Please, that's all I need!
うー! (キレてるよ!) はー! (キレてるよ!)
Woo! (You're getting it!) Ha! (You're getting it!)
筋肉にお願い
Please give me muscles soon!
くっつけるように腹筋を 収縮！収縮！ できたら戻して逆側も！
Bring your abs together, contract! contract! And back, now do the other side!
足と足と逆の肘を くっつけるように腹筋を 収縮！収縮！
Foot to foot and opposite elbow, bring your abs together, contract! contract!
できたら戻してもう1回！
And back, one more time!
足と足と逆の肘を くっつけるように腹筋を 収縮！収縮！
Foot to foot and opposite elbow, bring your abs together, contract! contract!
筋肉にお願いだ！
To your muscles, we pray!
はい、サイドチェストーー！
Yes, side chest!
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたい
Gotta get muscle, dying to be popular
お願いマッスル めっちゃ痩せたい
Gotta get muscle, dying to lose weight
お願いマッスル めっちゃモテたいならウー！
Gotta get muscle, if you want to be popular, ooh!
キレてるよ！
You're ripped!
筋肉にお願いだ！
Pray to the muscles!
ヒップレイズ！サイドベント！ 腹筋板チョコ！ ダンベルカール！ハンマーカール！
Hip raise! Side bend! Shredded chocolate abs! Dumbbell curl! Hammer curl!
これが二頭の新時代！
This is the new era of biceps!
プッシュアップ！ ベンチプレス！はち切れそうな大胸筋！
Push up! Bench press! Ready to burst pecs!
サイドクランク！ハイクリーン！出たなプロポーションおばけ！
Side plank! High clean! Look at that proportion monster!
レッグカール！ハックリフト！ザッツアグレート大腿筋！
Leg curl! Hack lift! That's a great quadriceps!
バックプレス！サイドレイズ！とれたて新鮮肩メロン！
Back press! Side raise! Fresh-picked shoulder melons!
ベントオーバー！ラットプルダウン！背中に世界を背負ってる！
Bent-over! Lat pulldown! Carrying the world on your back!
仕上がってるよ！仕上がってるよ！頑張るあなたは美しい！
You're all set! Your hard work is beautiful!
お願いマッスル
Gotta get muscle
BANG! BANG! バカンス！
BANG! BANG! Vacance!
シャワー浴びて真夜中 クーラーのリモコン握りしめ
Taking a shower at midnight, clutching the AC remote
ぜーぜー言ってた去年の夏 バイクの免許欲しいな
Panting last summer, I want a motorcycle license
そしたらバイクも欲しいな でも結局うだうだしてた去年の夏
And then I want a bike too, but after all I dithered away last summer
バカンスって言葉の半分はバカバカバカ
Half of the word "vacance" is just baka, baka, baka
どうせバカなら元気なバカがいい
If I'm gonna be a fool, I might as well be an energetic one
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! 裸足でgo now 人類の進化に逆らって
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! Go barefoot now, defying human evolution
バカンス、ステイ！言葉の半分はばかんばかんばかんばか
Vacance, stay! Half of the words are baka, baka, baka
どうせバカなら元気なバカがいい
If I'm gonna be a fool, I might as well be an energetic one
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! 剥がしでゴーな
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! Strip and go now
ズルいの神様見守って
God of cunning, watch over us
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! おバカズラで
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! With a foolish face
スーツで海に飛び込んで
Diving into the ocean in a suit
さあ太陽と打ち合わせしよう
Come on, let's coordinate with the sun
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! 剥がしでゴーな
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! Strip and go now
世界平和もプライドも捨てて
Throwing away world peace and pride
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! おバカズラで
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! With a foolish face
買い込んで国際線のチャット
Buying up international flight chats
もう恋なんて現地調達
Finding love locally right away
計画通りなんか進まない
Things never go according to plan
それがバカのバカンス
That's the vacation of a fool
うちに着くまで激バカでいい
It's fine to be super silly until we get home
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! 剥がしでゴーな
baby BANG! BANG! BANG! Strip and go now
サングラスを頭に乗っけちゃって
Putting sunglasses right on top of our heads
シャワーぶっ壊れ真夜中
Shower broken in the middle of the night
クーラーのリモコン握りしめ
Clinging to the air conditioner remote
ぜーぜー言ってた去年の夏
Panting, last summer
バイクの免許欲しいな
Want a motorcycle license
そしたらバイクも欲しいな でも
And then I want a motorcycle too, but
結局うだうだしてた一昨年の夏
After all, hemming and hawing the summer before last
バカンスって言葉の半分はバカバカバカ
Half of the word vacation is baka baka baka
どうせバカなら元気なバカがいい
Anyway, if you're a baka, an energetic baka is good
baby bang! bang! bang! 裸足でgo now
baby bang! bang! bang! go now barefoot
人類の進化に逆らって
Defying human evolution
baby bang! bang! bang! oh! バカづらで
baby bang! bang! bang! oh! with a foolish face
スーツで海に飛び込んで
Jumping into the ocean in a suit
さあ太陽と打ち合わせしよう
Come on, let's coordinate with the sun
男前だね 木村くん
That's manly, Kimura-kun
当たり前だよ 前田さん
Naturally, Maeda-san
前田さんなんてウチにはいない
Maeda-san isn't at our place
（まじで？）
(Seriously?)
バイクの免許欲しいな
Want a motorcycle license
（まだいってんの？）
(Still saying that?)
だけど歯医者へも行かなくちゃ でも
But I gotta go to the dentist too, but
結局うだうだしそう今年の夏
After all, probably hemming and hawing this summer
痛いことは嫌いですが
Though I hate painful things,
君の手の平は嫌いじゃない
I don't hate the palm of your hand.
言葉は飴玉みたいに
Words are like hard candy,
甘く広がってココロ満たす
Spreading sweetly and filling my heart.
嗚呼 全然分かってない
Ah, you completely don't understand
永遠に言う通り
Always as you say
完全にフェアじゃない
Completely unfair
（どこにいても）
(Wherever you may be)
嗚呼「なんで？」は効いてない
Ah, "why?" has no effect
もっともっとあの子みたいに可愛くなくちゃ
I gotta be way cuter than that girl
愛情は聡明に 傷跡はHow many?
Love is wise, scars are how many?
もう体躯痛いのだって分かんなくなる
My body hurts so much I can't even tell anymore
延命マタタビ 週二ご褒美
Prolonging life catnip, twice-weekly reward
「もう嫌んなった」って離されないように
So I won't be let go with "I'm sick of you"
今日だってちゃんと内緒の毛づくろい にゃって良い子にするから
Today too, secret grooming like a good kitty, so
愛して
Love me
Everybody today is rubbing day
Get it get it this is my courtship
Any any any time is fine with me
Gimme gimme love me, my darling
会いたいを間違いなんて皆は言う 取り憑かれているって
Everyone says wanting to see you is a mistake, that I'm possessed
ならこの胸で疼く 締め付けるような切なさは何なの？
Then what is this painful, tightening ache in my chest?
選ぶ言葉 戸惑う指先 端正な横顔
Choosing words, hesitating fingertips, a neat profile
（私も知らない）
(Even I don't know)
嗚呼 ランダムご機嫌
Ah, random good mood
もしかして今日は優しく撫でてくれるのかな？
Could it be today you'll pet me gently?
君のソレが耐えられるの 生涯で私だけなんだよね
I'm the only one in my lifetime who can endure your thing
あからさまに カラダまさに 「もう嫌だ」って離られないよね
Blatantly, physically, can't leave saying "I hate it"
そうだよね？
Right?
感情は上々に 訴えは少々に
Emotions are high, complaints are few
もうLieも賽のように転がせば良い
Even lies can roll like dice
柑橘の匂いだて凌ぐのだ もう噛んだって叱られるだけだし
Surpassing even citrus scent, now biting just gets me scolded
今日だってちゃんと お膝で大人しく にゃってお好きなように 完全淘汰して
Today too, quietly on your lap, like a kitty as you like, completely eliminating
はーい！みんな見て！
Hi everyone, look!
キャットラビングからののえちゃん、なんとね、猫耳つけております！
After "Cat Loving", Noel-chan is, you see, wearing cat ears!
つけ猫耳！いっぱいスクショ撮ってね！いぇーい！
Clip-on cat ears! Take lots of screenshots! Yay!
ちょっといつもと違うようなね、曲を歌って、ひひななんですけど、でもかわいいですな、
I sang a song a bit different from usual, hee-hee, but it's cute, right?
でもかわいいけどね、ちょっといろいろまだまだありますので、ちょ、ちょっとね、つけ猫耳を
It's cute, but there's still a lot more, so, um, I'll take off the clip-on cat ears
取ってきますので、しばしお待ちください。
and be right back, so please wait a moment.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
取れたなと、あい！
It's off. Yay!
いや、ちょっとなんか名残惜しいんですけど、
Well, it's kind of bittersweet, but
この衣装はですね、ライト衣装になっております！
this costume is, you see, the light costume!
さっきまで水着着てたからちょっとね、なんか、暑いなって感じなんですけど、
Until earlier I was wearing a swimsuit, so I feel kind of hot, but
まあ、これからね、もーっと暑い夏にしていきましょう！
well, from now on, let's make it an even hotter summer!
そして大さん、他にも気付いたところありますよね？そう、見てください！このステージすごーい！
And Dsan, aren't there other things you noticed? That's right, look! This stage is amazing!
皆さん初めてね、見たと思いますけど、
I think everyone's seeing it for the first time, but
今回、夏のね、この4周年ライブに向けてステージを作っていただきました！ありがとうございます！
this time, for the 4th anniversary summer live, they built this stage for us! Thank you!
しかも、なんと上にね、大さんもいるんですよ！
And what's more, Dsan is up there too!
なんかね、グリ溜めてるね（笑）
They're hoarding chestnuts, lol.
いや、かわいい、モグモグしてる！
Awn, so cute, they're munching!
え、大さん、そこから見守っててね！あ、かわいい！
Eh, Dsan, watch over me from up there! Ah, cute!
いや、すごい特等席からのえちゃんのことをみまもってくれてありがとう！かわいいね！
Wow, thanks for watching over Noel-chan from such a special seat! So cute!
あの、大さんね、ぜひぜひ、あの、ご飯食べたりね、色々しながらのえちゃんのライブ楽しんでください！
And Dsan, please enjoy Noel's live while eating meals and doing various things!
ちょっと服、ちょっと着たいなって思うんですけど。
I feel like changing my clothes a bit.
じゃあ、ちょっと着替えますか？
So shall we change?
ちょっとあっついんでね、ちょっと色々衣装があるのでね、ではちょっと1回ぴゃっ
It's a bit hot, and I have various outfits, so let's do a quick...
ちょっとのえさんの着替えてるとこ見ないでっ。
Hey, don't peek while Noel is changing!
よしよし、どぅるるるるるるんっ。
Alright alright, durururururun!
よしよし、脱ぎ脱ぎ、おっ。
Alright, stripping off, oh!
いつでも大丈夫だよん。
Anytime is fine.
あいっということでね、新衣装一緒になりました！
Alright, so I've changed into my new outfit!
いや、ちょっとね、さっきよりも涼しげな感じになっておるんですけど、
Well, it feels a bit cooler than before,
ま、次はね、どんな曲を歌うのか、そしてもしやして誰かと歌うかも？
but what kind of song will I sing next? And maybe I'll sing with someone?
と言うことでね、ぜひ、あの、最後まで聞いてってください。
So please, make sure to listen all the way to the end.
ライブまだまだ続くよ！それじゃあ歌います！
The live goes on! So here I go!
パークっとしたいわ 端から端まで結ばれたいな
I want to PAKU, I want to be tied from end to end,
パークっとしたいわ 指先と言葉で伝えたいな
I want to PAKU, I want to convey it with fingertips and words.
パークっとしたいわ わがままかも知れないアンサーで
I want to PAKU, with a selfish answer perhaps,
パークっとしたいわ どっちもどっちにしたいな
I want to PAKU, I want to make both sides equal.
ただただ問答 間違ってんのはどっち？
Just questions and answers, which one is wrong?
え、スマイルは0円です でも心は擦り減ってくようです
Eh, smiles are free, but my heart seems to be wearing down.
あーあ マシンソウル一兆回ローリングサンダー貫通ムービングドラペンティ 本当のフェイスに誰か気づいてんだ
Ah, a machine soul, a trillion rolling thunders, has anyone noticed my real face?
冗談めった言葉で案外本心です
In joking words, it's unexpectedly my true feeling.
だって歌ってそういうもんでしょってネットの掲示板で読んだよ
Because singing is just like that, I read on the internet bulletin board.
くさってるんじやなんとか生きてけそうかもしれない どうかと思うけどこれが私
Rotting away, somehow I might survive, though I wonder if this is me.
アーエーばこうゆう パークっとしたいわ
Ah-yeah, something like this. I want to PAKU,
端から端まで結ばれたいな パークっとしたいわ
I want to be tied from end to end. I want to PAKU,
指先と言葉で伝えたいな パークっとしたいわ
I want to convey it with fingertips and words. I want to PAKU,
わがままかも知れないアンサーで パークっとしたいわ
with a selfish answer perhaps. I want to PAKU,
どっちもどっちにしたいな
I want to make both sides equal.
繰り出す針線で連打連打 身動き取れないなたいだたいだ
Sending out needle threads, unable to move at all.
It's the tomorrow morning I heart discommunication my coder
ああ全然ないなバケーション完熟ルーティン生搾りの柑橘系温ディス難です気抜いたらキューパーです
Ah, not at all, a vacation, fully ripe routine, freshly squeezed citrus, if you let your guard down it's 9%.
そう息継ぎさせたってわない問題です 通過実感ともなって終わってる現在進行形も
That's a non-issue, the current progressive where the sense of passing has ended too.
フラストな感情どっかに行っちゃった 宝物はなに？捨てるつもりもないのにさ
Frustrated emotions went somewhere. What's my treasure? Even though I have no intention of throwing it away.
アーエーばこうゆう パークっとしたいわ
Ah-yeah, something like this. I want to PAKU,
端から端まで結ばれたいな パークっとしたいわ
I want to be tied from end to end. I want to PAKU,
指先と言葉で伝えたいな パークっとしたいわ
I want to convey it with fingertips and words. I want to PAKU,
わがままかも知れないアンサーで パークっとしたいわ
with a selfish answer perhaps. I want to PAKU,
どっちもどっちにしたいな
I want to make both sides equal.
音から意味まで結ばれたいな パークっとしたいわ
I want to be tied from sound to meaning. I want to PAKU,
確かなことだけ見つからないや パークっとしたいわ
Only certain things cannot be found. I want to PAKU,
おのおのから繋がれアンサーで パークっとしたいわ
connected from each to each with an answer. I want to PAKU,
どっちもどっちにしたいな
I want to make both sides equal.
キラキラ光ってるはずなんだ
It's supposed to be glittering and shining,
ワールドワイドワンダー
World Wide Wonder!
キャキャキャ キャパシティオーバーで 毎晩毎日だ
Capacity overloaded every single night and day!
頭ごんがらがってワーニングワーニング
My head is all mixed up, warning, warning!
でっかいスキルの上にウサギがいるんだって
On top of a huge skill, there's a rabbit, they say,
宇宙旅行にパスポートで入りますか
shall we enter space travel with a passport?
僕らが歩いてく世界の 明日は何色？
What color is tomorrow in the world we walk through?
キミと僕で描いていく ふたり色
The two-color palette painted by you and me.
チェックメイトキミをチェックメイト
Checkmate, checkmate you!
会いたい時には会いに行くよ 地球の中から夢の中まで
When I want to see you, I'll go meet you, from inside the earth to inside our dreams.
キラキラ スカートが揺れる 演奏とキミを演奏と
Glittering skirt swaying, playing music and you, playing music and—
マニュアル通りじゃつまらないでしょ
Just following the manual is boring, right?
不安しかなかった希望があるってこと キラキラ光ってるはずなんだ
The fact that there was only anxiety means there's hope—it's supposed to be glittering and shining,
ワールドワイドワンダー
World Wide Wonder!
エモーションじゃなんでもありのアイドルだ 常識もぐらついちゃってパニックパニック
An idol where anything goes with emotion, common sense wobbling, panic, panic!
深海の底で人魚が恋をして 嘘か本当か確かめにきませんか
At the bottom of the deep sea, a mermaid falls in love—won't you come check if it's a lie or truth?
僕らが暮らしてる世界は ひとりひとつの色
The world we live in is one color per person.
それはお父さんお母さんの 愛の色
That is the color of love from mom and dad.
きらきら、光ってるはずなんだ
Sparkling, it should be shining bright,
キャパシティオーバー
capacity over!
てんてこまいの毎日だ
It's a frantic everyday life,
頭こんががって warning warning
my head all mixed up, warning, warning!
でっかい月の上にウサギがいるんだっけ?
Is there a rabbit on the big moon?
宇宙旅行にパスポートって要りますか
Do we need a passport for space travel?
ぼくらが歩いていくセカイの明日はどんな色?
What color is tomorrow in the world we walk?
君と僕で描いていくふたりいろ
Painted in the colors of you and me.
I shall checkmate
君を checkmate
checkmate you!
会いたい時には会いにいくよ
When I want to see you, I'll go see you,
地球の裏から夢の中まで
from the other side of Earth into dreams.
ひらひら、スカートが揺れる
Fluttering, my skirt sways,
escort 君を escort
escorting, escorting you!
マニュアル通りじゃつまらないでしょ?
Wouldn't it be boring by the manual?
不安の数だけ希望があるってこと
That means hope equals our anxiety.
胸の奥がキュッとなる
My heart tightens deep inside,
消えない消せない過去も笑えるように
so unerasable pasts can make me smile.
未来が僕らを呼んでる
The future is calling out to us,
ほら踊れる曲は踊っとくのが楽しむコツ
see, dancing to any song is the key to fun!
I shall checkmate
君を checkmate
checkmate you!
会いたい時には会いにいくよ
When I want to see you, I'll go see you,
机の奥から22世紀まで
from deep in the desk to the 22nd century.
ふらふら、旅してる途中
Wandering along on a journey,
escort
escorting,
君を escort
escorting you!
マニュアル通りじゃつまらないでしょ?
Wouldn't it be boring by the manual?
不安の数だけ希望があるってこと
That means hope equals our anxiety.
高く高く跳べる気がしてるんだ
I feel like I can jump higher and higher.
escort
escorting,
君を escort
escorting you!
マニュアル通りじゃつまらないでしょ?
Wouldn't it be boring by the manual?
不安の数だけ希望があるってこと
That means hope equals our anxiety.
無理も通せば道理がなんとなら
If pushing through unreason makes sense somehow,
高く高く跳べる気がしてるんだ
I feel like I can jump higher and higher.
I shall checkmate
君を checkmate
checkmate you!
会いたい時には会いにいくよ
When I want to see you, I'll go see you,
キラキラ、光ってるはずなんだ
sparkling, it should be shining bright.
曖昧事件に付き合う朝14ポンドを吠える萎えぽん
Morning dealing with a vague incident, barking 14 lbs.
「何処しようもないけれど」気が狂う人のふりをしてる君を観ている
"There's nothing we can do," watching you pretend to go mad.
曖昧、面倒だったから切り捨てた4U型サイズを掬う烙印
Vague and troublesome, so I cut off—a brand scooping 4U size.
「申し訳ないけれど」擦れ違うものに無用にも期待を背負わせている
"I'm sorry, but" I needlessly burden passing things with hopes.
夜更かしはアイドの暴走
Staying up late is an idol's runaway,
目に焼き付いた青の感光
blue photosensitivity burned into my eyes.
モラトリアム的人生
A moratorium-like life,
最大公約数緩衝材
greatest common divisor cushion.
食べてすぐ寝て醜になる
Eating and sleeping right away makes me ugly,
起きてまた寝て人であなし?
waking up to sleep again, am I even human?
失敗!
Failure!
急転 相まって壊したって出た狂うなんてこと
Sudden turn, breaking together into madness.
死んでしまう! 鳴らすのミアモール感じ絡め
I'm gonna die! Ringing my amour, entangled in feelings,
サンクコスト、サンクコスト、遠い姉妹や取り戻したい手前
sunk cost, sunk cost, distant sisters or what we want back.
限界が来たら墜ちる墜ちる、足音ラミアンパラス
When limits come, we fall and fall, Lamia Paras' footsteps.
帰りFar away
Heading far away back home.
ゅて愛持って壊したって出た狂うなんてこと
Breaking with love, going crazy,
死んでしまう! 鳴らすのミアモール感じ絡め
I'm gonna die! Ringing my amour, entangled in feelings,
サンクコスト、サンクコスト、遠い姉妹や取り戻したい手前
sunk cost, sunk cost, distant sisters or what we want back.
帰りFar away
Heading far away back home.
朝の実験のアラームで蘇生した
Resuscitated by the morning experiment's alarm,
その間隙叫ぶ14ポンド
shouting 14 pounds in that interval.
「何処しようもないね」狂人の真似をしている君に言う
"There's nothing we can do," I tell you acting like a madman.
「簡単すぎる言葉 それを信じていたいなら」
"If you want to believe words that are way too simple,"
物足りない
it's not enough.
「心から申し訳ないなら することあるでしょ」
"If you're truly sorry, there's something you should do."
君にとって同じに見える音に答え見つける気もしない
I don't even care to find answers in sounds that seem the same to you.
曖昧事件に繰り出すアラーム急転
Alarms rushing out to vague incidents, sudden turns,
ロンロンを笑うレット
red laughing at ronron.
どうしようもないから気が狂う人の真似をしている君へ
To you, who pretend to go mad because nothing can be done,
簡単なこと、もしいちゃいたいなら足りないよ
it's simple—if you want to be together, it's not enough.
もしけないならすぐに後に振り返りば元戻れないよ
If you shouldn't, turning back right now means no return.
語気を登ぼそ、手に貼りついたおの残像
Raising my voice, the afterimage of an axe stuck to my hand.
モラトリアム的人間最初交差する弾道
Moratorium humans, the first intersecting trajectories.
食べてすぐ寝て醜になる
Eating and sleeping right away makes me ugly,
起きてまた寝て人であなし?
waking up to sleep again, am I even human?
マキシマイザー、マキシマイザー!
Maximizer, maximizer!
ゅて愛持って壊したって出た狂うなんてこと
Breaking with love, going crazy,
死んでしまう! 鳴らすのミアモール感じ絡め
I'm gonna die! Ringing my amour, entangled in feelings,
サンクコスト、サンクコスト、遠い姉妹や取り戻したい手前
sunk cost, sunk cost, distant sisters or what we want back.
限界が来たら墜ちる墜ちる、足音ラミアンパラス
When limits come, we fall and fall, Lamia Paras' footsteps.
帰りFar away
Heading far away back home.
ゅて愛持って壊したって出た狂うなんてこと
Breaking with love, going crazy,
死んでしまう! 鳴らすのミアモール感じ絡め
I'm gonna die! Ringing my amour, entangled in feelings,
サンクコスト、サンクコスト、遠い姉妹や取り戻したい手前
sunk cost, sunk cost, distant sisters or what we want back.
限界が来たら墜ちる墜ちる、足音ラミアンパラス
When limits come, we fall and fall, Lamia Paras' footsteps.
帰りFar away
Heading far away back home.
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Couldn't beat her smile, it stirred up all the media
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Secret side, I wanna know it, so mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even that elusive side, part of her controlled area
完璧で嘘つきな君は
Complete and perfect, all you say is a bunch of lies
天才的なアイドル様
Dear miss genius idol, unmatched
今日何食べた?
Today, what did you eat?
好きな本は?
What book do you love?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
Whenever you go out for fun, tell me, where do you go?
何も食べてない それは内緒
Haven't eaten anything, it's a secret, unknown
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Any questions you're facing, always acting so vaguely
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So unconcerned, although you brightly glow
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
Any seemingly unveiled secrets are as sweet as honey
あれもないないない これもないないない
Confusing, why, why, why? Essential, lie, lie, lie
好きなタイプは? 相手は? さあ答えて
So what is your type of guy? Any partner? So, now, answer this
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からないからさ」
I don't have any idea how I could love anyone
嘘か本当か知り得ないそんな言葉に
Cannot find out if it's true or it's a lie
また一人堕ちる また好きにさせる
Once again, there's somebody who's fallen for the words and cues
誰もが目を奪われていく
That emotion melts all hearts, all eyes on you
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
Cause you are perfect, the most ultimate idol
金輪際現れない
Unrivaled, will not appear again
一番星の生まれ変わり
It's the brightest star reborn, yes, indeed
その笑顔で愛してるで
Using that smiling face, that I love you again
誰もかも虜にしていく
Now, everybody is lured and captivated by you
その瞳が その言葉が
The pupil that you got, the words that you vocalize
嘘でもそれは完璧なアイ
Even when untrue, it's your perfect AI
はいはいあの子は特別です
Right, right, we all know she's very special, yes
我々はハナからおまけです
We had lost the fight before it started, so impressed
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're serving as support to her grace
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
Cannot tell me everything was because of her
しゃらくさい 妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
No, it's not right, out of line
これはネタじゃない からこそ許せない
How can we not feel jealous while being around?
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
It's not a joke, you know, right?
自分許せない 誰よりも強い
Completely deny imperfect your that I sight
君以外は認めない 誰もが信じあがめてる
I won't allow anyone if it's not you, strongest of all
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
That emotion seized all hearts worshipping you, yes, indeed
弱点なんて見当たらない
So strong, it's you, unrivaled idol
一番星を宿している
There can not be weaknesses to find
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
The brightest star is residing in you
知りたいここは見せずに唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
The gaps and shortcomings, don't show 'em, dammit, dammit
それこそ本物の愛
Parts nobody wants to know should remain hidden
得意の笑顔で和らすメディア
Showing this smile, my own weapon, boiling media
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
Keeping everything about my secret deep inside
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
I'm in love with you, my career is built on such a lie
これこそ私なりの愛だ
It's the way I know to show my love, without a doubt
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Running down, my sweat is flowing, cleanest aqua, right?
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
Ruby hidden under my eyelids where it resides
歌い踊り舞い私たちはマリア
I sing and dance around, look at me, I'm Maria
そう嘘は飛び切りの愛だ
So, lying surely is the greatest kind of love
誰かに愛されたことも
I recall no one that loved me whole before
誰のことも愛したこともない
And I've not been in love with anybody before
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること信じている
Now, the lies I am making up, I'm hoping that a day comes when they all become true
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
One day, I will hold everything that I pursue
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Yes, I am so greedy, true voracious idol
等身大でみんなのことをちゃんと愛したいから
So, sincerely, what I'm wishing for is to love each of you with all my heart
今日も嘘をつくの この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
And so, today, I lie again, the words I vocalize inside of me
それでもまだ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
I'm wishing that one day they come true
やっと言えた これは絶対嘘じゃない愛してる
I said it at last, I know it's not a lie as I'm voicing these words
誰もが逆らえずに潜っていく
No one can resist the urge to delve deeper
その目を灯火より輝かせて
Eyes shining brighter than torchlight
目指す先は深く
Our destination is deep
真っ直ぐに迷い込む
Losing our way, we dive on through
口開けた奈落の罠
The open mouth of this hellhole
真実のあとを追いかけよう
Let us press on, pursuing the truth!
今答えが見つかるなら全部なくしてもいい
If we can find an answer now, I don't mind sacrificing everything
その声を離さないようにこだまがまだ響いている
So that our voices won't stray, we keep their echoes reverberating
羅針盤はざっと闇を指したまま
Our compass point forever into the darkness
逃げ場のない方へ それが呪いでも
To where there's no escape, even it's a curse
鼓動は本物 二度と憧れは止まらない
This racing in our hearts is real
二度と憧れは止まらない
Desire will never stop again
かたち
[Title: Katachi]
歌声のやむときは
When our singing voices cease,
文明の終わり
at the end of civilization,
そっとだけ決めていた
I quietly decided it alone.
理由はわからない
The reason I don't know,
君の忘れるほど転がってるのに
yet it's scattered about as much as you forget.
憧れの輪郭は遠ざかってくみたい
The outline of longing seems to be fading away.
溢れるよほら手のひらに握りかえしてくれ
Overflowing, look, take it back in your palm.
痛みと痛みを取り替えよう
Let's exchange pain for pain,
勝手に進んだ仲の欠片すべて傷ついても僕は
and even if every fragment of our path is wounded, I will—
肩どっていく形になるための先で行こう
go beyond, to become the shape we trace.
響かせてよ
Make it resound!
旅の左手、最果ての右手
[Title: Left Hand of Journey, Right Hand of Farthest Reach]
空に浮かんでいる光る波を
Waves of light floating in the sky,
束ねて虹の橋をかけよう
let's gather them and build a rainbow bridge.
危うい足場滑るスロープ
A precarious footing, a slippery slope,
過去と未来の道標
signposts of the past and future.
君の左手、僕の右手を
Your left hand, my right hand—
繋いで繋げてはじめよう
let's connect them, tie them together, and begin!
いつもそばにいるよ
I will always be by your side,
過去も今も未来も
in the past, the present, and the future,
だから迷わずに歩いていこう
so let's walk forward without hesitation!
色とりどりの夢重ねて
Layering dreams of various colors,
明日はどこに向かう
where are we heading tomorrow?
君と一緒にいれたら世界は輝きだすよ
If I can be with you, the world will begin to shine!
最果ての地に咲く花を探そう
Let's search for the flower blooming in the farthest land.
夜明けが近い薄明かりに
In the dim light close to dawn,
耳をすませば風が歌う
if you strain your ears, the wind sings.
秘密教えて覗くスコープ
Tell me a secret, peering through the scope,
祈る奇跡が叶うなら
if the miracle I pray for comes true.
旅の装備は身軽じゃなくちゃね
Traveling equipment needs to be light, huh?
希望と絆があれば何もなくていいよ
As long as we have hope and bonds, it's fine even with nothing else.
星も空も光も君の声を頼りに
No stars, no sky, no light—relying on your voice,
さあ！行こう
come on, let's go!
止まらない憧れ重ねて
Unstoppable yearnings layered together,
明日は続いていく
tomorrow will continue.
帰り道さえ見えない世界を超えて行こうよ
Let's go beyond the world where even the way back cannot be seen!
見果てぬ夢に咲く花を探そう
Let's search for the flower blooming in an unseen dream.
柔らかな心に宿る意志は強く
The will dwelling in a soft heart is strong,
鋼のように結ばれた想い飛んでいけどこまでも高く
feelings bound together like steel, flying away high anywhere!
飛び込んでいけどこまでも
Flying in, anywhere...
空に浮かんでる光る波を
Let's tie together the waves of light floating in the sky
束ねて虹の橋をかけよう
And build a rainbow bridge
危ない足場 滑るスロープ
A dangerous foothold, a slippery slope
過去と未来の道しるべ
A guidepost of the past and future
君の左手 ぼくの右手
Your left hand, my right hand
繋いでつないではじめよう
Let's connect them and begin
いつもそばにいるよ
I am always by your side
過去も今も未来も
In the past, present, and future
だから迷わずに歩いていこう
So let's walk on without hesitation
いろどりどりの夢重ねて
Layering colorful dreams
明日はどこに向かう
Where is tomorrow heading?
君と一緒にいられたら世界は輝きだすよ
If I can be together with you, the world will start to shine
最果ての地に咲く花を探そう
Let's search for the flower blooming in the farthest land
帰り道 ふざけて歩いた
We joked around on our way home.
訳も無く 君を怒らせた
I made you angry for no reason.
色んな君の 顔を見 たかったんだ
I guess I just wanted to see your different sides.
大きな瞳が 泣きそうな声が
Your large eyes, your trembling voice,
今も ぼくの 胸を 締め付ける
Even now they are close by my heart.
すれ違う 人の中で 君を 追いかけた
In the crowd of strangers, I ran after you.
変わらないもの 探していた
I was searching for the things that never change.
あの日の君を 忘れはしない
I will never forget how you were on that day.
時を超えてく 想いがある
These feelings I have transcend time.
ぼくは 今すぐ 君に会いたい
I just want to meet you now.
街灯に ぶら下げた 想い
These feelings upon which the street lights shine,
いつも君に 渡せなかった
I could never manage to let you have them.
夜は ぼく達を 遠ざけていたね
The nights brought us further away from each other.
見えない心で 嘘付いた声が
The lie you told through your opaque heart,
今も ぼくの胸に 響いている
Even now it continues to resonate within me.
さまよう時の中で 君と 恋をした
Uncertain of our future, you and I fell in love.
変わらないもの 探し ていた
I was searching for the things that never change.
あの日 見つけた 知らない 場所へ
The unfamiliar place we found on that day,
君と二人で 行けるのなら
If the two of us can go there together again,
ぼくは 何度も 生まれ変われる
I will be reborn as many times as it takes.
形ないもの 抱きしめてた
As I embrace the things that have no shape,
壊れる音も 聞こえないまま
I fail to hear the breaking sound.
君と歩いた 同じ道に
On the same path that we walked together,
今も灯りは 照らし続ける
Even now the light continues to shine.
変わらないもの 探 し ていた
I was searching for the things that never change.
あの日の君を 忘れはしない
I will never forget how you were on that day.
時を超えてく 想いがある
These feelings I have transcend time.
ぼくは 今すぐ 君に会いたい
I just want to meet you now.
街頭にぶら下げた想い
When I was hanging my feelings down from street lamps,
いつも君には渡せなかった
I was never able to pass them on to you.
夜はぼくたちを遠ざけていたね
The nights were distancing us apart.
見えない心で嘘ついた声が
The voice telling lies with an invisible heart,
今もぼくの胸に響いている
Still resonates in my chest.
さまよう時の中で君と恋をした
I fell in love with you in the drifting time.
変わらないもの探していた
I was searching for something unchangeable.
あの日の君を忘れはしない
I will never forget you from that day.
時を超えてく想いがある
There are feelings that transcend time.
ぼくは今すぐ君に会いたい
I want to see you right now.
形ないもの抱きしめてた
Embracing something formless,
壊れる音も聞こえないまま
Without even hearing the sound of breaking,
君と歩いた同じ道に
On the same path we walked together,
今も明かりは照らし続ける
The lights continue to shine even now.
変わらないもの探していた
I was searching for something unchangeable.
あの日の君を忘れはしない
I will never forget you from that day.
時を超えてく想いがある
There are feelings that transcend time.
ぼくは今すぐ君に会いたい
I want to see you right now.
変わらないものを探していた
I was searching for something unchanging...
あの日の君を 忘れはしない
I will never forget you from that day.
時を超えてく 思いがある
There are feelings that transcend time.
僕は今すぐ 君に会いたい
I want to see you right now.
はあ、もうすっかり夜になっちまった。
Ha, it's already completely nighttime.
なんかすごいね、しみじみした。なんか夏の夜っていう気持ちになっているんですが、
It feels so nostalgic and sentimental, like a summer night, but...
第3、ちょっとね、びっくりするようなことを今から言うので、ちょっと心臓、ちょっと爆発しないでくださいね。
Thirdly, I'm going to tell you something shocking, so please don't let your hearts explode.
なんと、団長ね、あの結構、周年やら誕生日で毎回お披露目してるものがあるんですけど、何だと思いますか？
Guess what? As for your leader, I always unveil something for my anniversaries and birthdays. What do you think it is?
うん、つんつんつんつんつん、そう です！今回もね、新曲を発表したいと思います！イエーイ！
Yeah, tsuntsuntsuntsun, that's right! This time too, I'd like to announce a new original song! Yay!
ええと、今回ですね、あの発表する曲なんですけど、タイトルが「ラフミータンダー」という曲になっておりまして、
Um, this time, the song I'm announcing is titled 'Love Me Tender',
作詞・作曲・編曲がなんと、かの有名なとことこ...さん、と、西沢さんPに作っていただきました！ありがとうございます！イエーイ！
and the lyrics, composition, and arrangement were done by the famous Tokotoko-san and Nishizawa-san-P! Thank you so much! Yay!
いやあね、もう本当に神曲いっぱいあるんですけど、今回のライブで、あのスバちゃんと歌った「ワールドワイドワンダー」がね、あの西沢さんPの曲なんですけど、
Well, you know, there are so many god-tier songs, but 'Worldwide Wonder' that I sang with Suba-chan in this live is Nishizawa-san-P's song, and...
なんでスバちゃんと歌ったかと言うと、団長一番好きな曲になるんですよね、西沢さんPの曲で一番好きななんですが、
Why did I sing it with Suba-chan? Because it's my absolute favorite song among Nishizawa-san-P's songs, my favorite,
まあ、団長、スバちゃんと歌いたかったっていうのはあるんだけど、一番は、団長がスバちゃんのことを、まあちょっと最推しになったきっかけのね、かの有名なスバちゃんのライブがあるんですけど、
well, part of it was that I wanted to sing with Suba-chan, but most importantly, there's that famous live performance by Suba-chan that became the catalyst for her becoming my absolute oshi...
そこいでね、団長、もう全部が好きだったんだけど、特に、あの「ヨモスガラ君オモウ」っていう西沢さんPの曲をね、スバちゃんが、あの歌って踊ってしてて、
And at that live, I loved everything about it, but especially when Suba-chan was singing and dancing to Nishizawa-san-P's 'Yomosugara Kimi Omou',
わりにちょっと惚れてしまったんでね、そういうちょっと点と点が結び合うみたいな感じで、あのスバちゃんと歌わせていただきました。
I fell a little bit in love right then and there. So, feeling like dots connecting, I got to sing it with Suba-chan.
そんな感じで色々な縁がありまして、今回、はい、新曲作っていただいたので、早速、あの、皆さんにお披露目したいと思います！それでは、聞いてください。「ラフミータンダー」！
With various such connections, since they made this new song for me this time, I'd love to premiere it for everyone right away! So, please listen to it. 'Love Me Tender'!
君に会いたい もっとちゃんと
I want to see you, properly,
ちっとちゃんと時間をかけて
taking enough time.
話せたらいいのに
If only we could talk...
いつも僕は焦ってばっか
I'm always just rushing.
言いたいことの半分も言えなくて
I can't even say half of what I want to say.
あのね 七転び八起きなんて言うけど
You know, they say 'fall seven times, stand up eight',
一回でも大きれたら上等
but getting back up even once is already a win.
でもね やるべきことって自分で知ってる
But you know, I know what I need to do myself.
そうだ答えはシンプルで
That's right, the answer is simple:
昨日の心配も 明日の憂鬱も
Yesterday's worries and tomorrow's gloom,
君と話せば笑い話になる
if I talk with you, they become funny stories.
どこにいても 何をしてても
No matter where I am, no matter what I'm doing,
声は届くよ 君方向へ
my voice reaches out toward you.
どんより曇りも しょんぼり気味も
Gloomy weather and downcast spirits,
君に語ればほらキラキラ光る
if I talk to you, look, they sparkle and shine.
嬉しい楽しいがもっと増えてく
Happiness and joy just keep increasing.
無邪気な子供のように抱きしめて
Embrace me like an innocent child.
位置について よーいどんで 周回遅れで
On your marks, get set, go—lapping behind,
明日は二周遅れ？
tomorrow, two laps behind?
あのね 理由もなく弱気になる日は
You know, on days when I feel weak for no reason,
ボロボロ疲れてる証拠
Evidence that I'm completely worn out,
でもね 笑う角には福も迎えに来てるかもって
but hey, maybe good fortune is coming to greet those who smile.
Oh Baby, What a Beautiful Day
うろ覚えな歌詞も
Even the lyrics I half-remember,
曖昧なメロディも
and the vague melody,
君と歌えば ほらね 一曲になる
if I sing them with you, look, they become a song.
友達以上 恋人未満より
More than friends, less than lovers,
名前のない 特別な距離
a nameless, special distance between us.
昨日の失敗も 明日の憂鬱も
Yesterday's failures and tomorrow's blues,
君と話せば 笑い話になる
if I talk with you, they turn into a funny story.
どこにいても 波乗りしてても
No matter where I am, or even if I'm riding waves,
声は飛んでく 君方向へ
my voice flies out toward you.
どんより雨降りも
Even gloomy, rainy days,
しょぼりな日暮も
and dreary dusks,
君に掛かれば ほら キラキラ光る
if it's up to you, look, they sparkle and shine.
嬉しい楽しいが もっと増えてく
Joy and fun keep increasing even more,
無邪気な子供のように 抱きしめて
holding me tight like an innocent child.
パッキュンパッキュン お手おない
Pakyun pakyun, hands up—
君に会いたい
I want to see you.
えーどうでしたか？ラフミーテンダーでしたー！
Um, how was it? That was Lafumee Tender!
いやー本当この日のためにね、ずっと本当描き下ろしていただいたので、ちょっとみんなさんにお披露目できてよかったです。
Man, they drew this specially for me for this day, so I'm so glad I could reveal it to everyone.
でね、ちょっとのえちゃん、ま、最後ね、ちょっとすごいエモエモな第3に届けるお曲をね、あの、まだ1曲あるんですけど
And you know, Noel-chan, finally, we have a very emotional song to deliver... though there's still one more song,
その前にちょっと2点ほど、ちょっと忘れてたので、あの、紹介というか、あの、いいですか？あの、ちょっとのえちゃん
before that, there are about two things I almost forgot, so can I introduce them? Um, Noel-chan—
今年もあの、モチーフのローン4周年記念グッズ出します！それでは、ドン！
This year too, we're releasing 4th-anniversary motif merch! Here it is, ta-da!
こちらです！
Here it is!
はい！いや、とってもいいでしょう！では1個1個ちょっと紹介していきたいと思います。
Yeah! It's super nice, right? Let's introduce them one by one.
よし、じゃあちょっとまずはですね、この中でちょっと長長的に一推しなんですけど
Alright, first, among these, as a leader, it's my top recommendation, but—
こちら、えっと、ラバーマットですね。
this is, um, the rubber mat.
えーと、すごいかっこいい。あの、長長、よく分かるかな？長長がね、まあ、すごいくかっこよくね、名手持って戦ってるシーンなんですけど、なんと！
It's super cool. Can you tell? The leader is fighting so coolly holding a spear, but what's more,
ちょっとちっちゃくね、あの団員さんも戦っていいます。こちら、ロスリ先生描き下ろしのラバーマットとなっております！
in small, the dain-san is also fighting here. This is a rubber mat newly drawn by Rosuri-sensei!
いやー、すごいね、かっこいい！そして次はこちら！ドン！
Man, it's so cool! And next is this! Ta-da!
えーっと、白銀聖騎士団の団員証。
Um, the Shirogane Holy Knight Order member ID card.
いや、これね、めちゃめちゃ、これ作りたかったんだよね！なんかさ、みんなさ、いろんなホロメンがさ、なんかそういうさ、証明書とか、なんとか証みたいな作ってるたびに、いや、団長もこういうの作りてえなって思いながら、
Man, I really wanted to make this! You know how whenever various holomembers make certificates or ID cards like that, I kept thinking, "I want the leader to make something like this too,"
早4年、ちょっとね、お待たせしましたと。
and after 4 quick years, keeping you waiting.
ちょっとお待たせしすぎたかもしれないんですが、こちらね、あのぜひ、あのゲットして、俺、団員なんだぞって、あの、アピールしてください。
I might have kept you waiting too long, but please definitely get this and proudly claim, "I'm a member of the Order!"
そして、こちらを入れるね、あの、ドン！IDカードホルダーもセットに、はい、ま、単品でも売ってるんですが、
And to put this in, ta-da! The ID card holder is also set—well, it's sold individually too,
はい、付いておきますので、これもぜひぜひ要チェックでございます。
but it comes with it, so please definitely check it out.
そしてこちら、ドン！えー、団員さんぬいぐるみキーホルダーver.2023ということで、
And this one, ta-da! The Dain-san plush keychain ver.2023,
こちらめちゃめちゃ、かっこいいしょ！つよつよですよ、つよつよ。あの、ダブルでこうやってね、団長も名手持ってるんですけど、このね、団員さんも名手を持ったかっこいいぬいぐるみになってるので、
this is super cool! Super strong! The leader holds a spear in both hands like this, and since these dain-san plushies are also holding spears and looking cool,
あの、ぜひゲットしてください。いや、本当にね、今回のテーマが、本当戦う団長ということで、ま、団員さんもね、一緒に団員証だったりとか、団員さんもね、つよつよなかっこいいしたりとかっていう感じで、
please definitely get it. Really, this time's theme is "fighting leader," so the dain-san also has the ID card and looks super strong and cool,
いや、4年立ったからね、4年立ったからそろそろ強くなろうということで、ええ、あのぜひゲットしてみてください。
so since 4 years have passed, it's about time we become strong, so um, please definitely try getting it.
そして、あの、ボイスも出ます！ドン！
And voice packs will also be released! Ta-da!
あの、こちらね、ASMRボイス「団長の膝枕でお昼寝♡」ということでね、あの、ぜひぜひ、ちょっとこれは内容恥ずかしいので、あの、ぜひ聞いた人の、はい、秘密ということで、
Um, this ASMR voice "Taking a nap on the leader's lap ♡"—since the content is a bit embarrassing, please keep it a secret among those who listened,
よろしくお願いします！はい、ということでね、あの、フルセットも
so please look forward to it! Yes, so the full set—
あるんですが、フルセットはま、こちらになります！はい、で、今回ね、フルセットをご購入していただいた方に特典2つあります。ちょっとすごいボリュームでごめんね。
there is one, but the full set is this! Yes, and for those who purchased the full set this time, there are two bonus items. Sorry for the huge volume.
えーっと、まず1つ目が、えっと、こちらなんですけど、ポストカード。あの、このポストカードはね、あのラバーマットのイラストを描いて下さったロスリ先生のね、あのちょっと表情が、表情がちょっと
Um, first is this postcard. This postcard features the expression by Rosuri-sensei who drew the rubber mat... the expression is a bit—
違うバージョンで、あの、なんと数量限定にはね、
In a different version, um, for the quantity-limited edition,
団長直筆でサインを書かせていただきます！
the captain will personally sign them!
あの、よろしくお願いします。
Um, thank you for your support.
ちょっとね、あの数量限定なので、あの、ちょっと、がんばれ、がんばれということで、はい、えっと
Since it's quantity-limited, um, I've got to work hard, so yes...
ちなみに通常版もね、あの、箔押しの複製になっております。
By the way, the regular version features foil-stamped replica signatures.
そして特典2つ目なんですが、こちらはねASMRボイスで、あの4周年ありがとうボイスになってます。日頃の感謝を込めまして、団長の想いを込めてね、あの、撮りましたのでぜひ聞いてください！
And for the second bonus, it's an ASMR voice pack, a 4th anniversary thank-you voice. With daily gratitude and the captain's feelings put into it, I recorded it, so please listen!
はい、この配信の後にね、カートオープンするので、ぜひゲットしてください！よろしくお願いします！
Yes, the cart opens right after this stream, so please get it! Thank you!
そしてね、この後、メンゲンをね、22時15分からやるんですが、なんと今回はスルー、3Dで、ちょっと噛んじゃった、3Dでね、あの、カラオケなので、はい、ぜひぜひわちゃわちゃ楽しみにしてください。
And after this, I have a membership stream at 22:15, and this time in 3D—I tripped on my words—in 3D, it's karaoke, so please look forward to having fun!
それではちょっと長くなったんですが、最後に、第3、そして今いるね、あの、ホロメンリスナーさんに、あの、思いを込めて歌いますので、最後の曲、聞いてみよー！
Now, it got a bit long, but lastly, with feelings for the 3rd, and all the holomem listeners here, I'll sing, so for the final song, let's hear it—!
想像なんてしてなかった現状
A reality I never could have imagined,
君もそう思った？
did you think so too?
“最高”で止まらないように更新したい
I want to update it so it doesn't stop at "the best."
叶えたい夢まで
Up to the dream I want to fulfill,
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
to a place no one has ever been before,
たどり着くまでは僕ら止まれない
until we reach it, we cannot stop.
多分しんどいけどどうかよろしくね
It'll probably be tough, but please treat me well.
僕だけじゃ作れないものを、僕とか君とか私とか恋とか愛とかまとめて全部、君を置いてどこかに行っちゃうとかありえないよ
Things that cannot be created by me alone—you, me, I, romance, love, putting it all together, leaving you behind somewhere is simply impossible.
君がくれた音に弾けた火花に
From the sparks that burst in the sound you gave me,
初めてからずっと恋しちゃってんだよ
ever since the very first time, I've been falling in love.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't even imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on too, just the two of us is best, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくなったよ
I got so single-minded I even wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to such a messy me.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't even imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人でそれがいいじゃん
From now on too, just the two of us, that's best, right?
妄想ふくらんでくストーリー干渉
Delusions inflating into a story, sentimental
焼けに凹んじゃって代償求めすぎはややよ
and feeling overly depressed, asking for too much compensation is a no-no.
終わんない愛の盟
An endless federation of love—
驚かせたいから内緒なんだ
I want to surprise you, so it's a secret.
君の愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと許さないよ
I won't forgive your love always winning over mine!
君以外はヤダわがままは
Anything besides you is a no. My selfishness is
ただ変わらないトキメキを
just for an unchanging excitement.
絶叫しちゃうのはバカ
Screaming out in despair is foolish.
君がくれた音に弾けた火花に
From the sparks that burst in the sound you gave me,
初めてからずっと恋しちゃってんだよ
ever since the very first time, I've been falling in love.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't even imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on too, just the two of us is best, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくなったよ
I got so single-minded I even wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to such a messy me.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't even imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人でそれがいいじゃん
From now on too, just the two of us, that's best, right?
君がくれた音に弾けた火花に
From the sparks that burst in the sound you gave me,
初めてからずっと恋しちゃってんだよ
ever since the very first time, I've been falling in love.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't even imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on too, just the two of us is best, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくなったよ、散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
I got so single-minded I even wanted to run away. Thank you for calling out to such a messy me.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ、これから先も二人でそれがいいじゃん
I can't even imagine a future without you. From now on too, just the two of us, that's best, right?
時々したいじゃんか誰だって
Everyone wants to do it from time to time, right?
あんどろいどがおかしくなっちゃった
An Android girl went completely crazy—
痛みのないキスが離れない僕らヴァンパイア
a kiss without pain won't leave us, we are vampires.
いいよ 吸い付しちゃっていいよ
It's fine, you can go ahead and bite.
もう無理無理だって悪い子じゃないこんな歌歌ったんだって
"I can't take any more," that's not it, I'm not a bad kid, that's why I sang this song—
君が輝けるように
so that you can shine brightly!
お願い マッスル
Please, Muscle!
めっちゃモテたい
I want to be super popular!
愛情は 聡明に
Love is wise and clear,
もう 体調 痛いのだって 分かんなくなる
I can't even tell if my body hurts anymore.
恋しくて 恋しくて しょうがない
I miss you so much I can't help it,
愛しいキミに 触れたくて
Wanting to touch my beloved you.
4周年ありがとうございます！！ 今日のLIVEは楽しんでもらえたでしょうか…！！
Thank you so much for 4 years!! Did you enjoy today's LIVE...?!
5年目も団長らしく進んでくので！ 団員さんも一緒にいてくれると嬉しいですっ✨
I'll keep moving forward like the leader I am in my 5th year! I'd be so happy if you members stay with me too✨
大すきだぁぁー！！
Love you so much!!